Guide to the Assistant Dean for Judicial Affairs and Educational Services records, 1936-1988 RG0047
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Assistant Dean for Judicial Affairs and Educational Services records
1936-1988
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington University. Office of the Assistant Dean for Judicial Affairs and Educational Services
RG0047
6.25 Linear Feet 13 boxes
The Assistant Dean for Judicial Affairs and Educational Services used to be part of the Dean of Student's Office of The George Washington University. Materials in this collection include student life committee minutes and constitution, joint committee of faculty and students records, and student court records.
Acquisition Information
Materials acquired through transfers from the Dean for Judicial Affairs and Educational Services.
Historical or Biographical Note
The Assistant Dean for Judicial Affairs and Educational Services used to be part of the Dean of Student's Office of The George Washington University. It is now under the Associate Vice President and Dean of Students, who reports to the Senior Vice President for Student and Academic Support Services. The office oversees student discipline and punishment for violations of University policies.
N.B. This history note was written in 2005
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include student life committee minutes and constitution, joint committee of faculty and students records, and student court records. They range in date from 1936-1988, and were transferred to the University Archives by the Dean for Judicial Affairs and Educational Services.
Students; Committees; Faculty; Washington (D.C.); Foggy Bottom (Washington, D.C.); George Washington University
- Student life committee, 1936-1980; Series 1
  - Standing committee - student life, 1954-1967; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Student life committee minutes, 1968-1969; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Standing committee - student life: general, 1968-1970; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Student life committee minutes, 1967-1968; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Student life committee, 1936-1970; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
    General
    Dates of material are 1936-1938 and 1964-1970.
  - Joint committee on student affairs, 1970-1971; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Student life committee, joint committee on student affairs, 1970; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Joint committee of faculty and students, 1971-1974; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2-8)
  - Joint committee, 1974-1980; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
  - Student life subcommittee on discrimination, 1968; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Groups and student organizations, 1965-1988; Series 2
  - Student-faculty dialogue, 1968; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Implementation of Human Relations Act, 1968-1970; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Academic evaluation, 1970; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Rules and regulations handbook, 1971-1972; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Steering committee for a university-wide assembly, 1973; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1968-1969; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Chicago 7 demonstration protest and police reaction, 1970; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Ad hoc hearing committee on student affairs, 1968-1971; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Student court openings, 1972; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Student traffic court charter, 1971; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Resident halls judicial system documents, 1971-1981; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 5-9)
  - Student faculty committee on appeals, 1971-1972; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Presidential appeals board, 1974; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Formation of the student affairs division, 1971-1972; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Student affairs annual report and student life on campus, 1977-1986; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Honors convocation planning, 1984-1985; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Students for a Democratic Society, 1968-1973; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Former student organizations, 1962-1968; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Students for Better Government, 1967-1968; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Student nominating board, 1974; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Student mobilization committee, 1971-1972; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Black People's Union history, 1968-1987; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Committee for the Campus, 1976-1977; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Co-Ops and Polyphony, 1977-1978; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - GW Eco-Action Washington Ecology Center, 1975; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - District of Columbia Public Interest Research Group (DCPIRG) at GW, 1972-1975; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 11-12)
  - Mortar Board, 1979; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Potomac magazine, 1965-1967; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Project Serve, 1966-1983; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - TIAA/CREF study committee, 1985-1988; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Student court [restricted], 1962-1979; Series 3
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains information on court cases, hearings and appeals from students. The records are covered by FERPA and are closed for 100 years.
  - Cassette tapes [Restricted], 1969-1974; Series 3 (Box 4)
    Conditions Governing Access
    These cassette tapes will need to be digitized, and also are covered by FERPA.
  - Student court records [Restricted], 1969-1974; Series 3 (Box 7, Folder 1-6)
    These materials are closed to researchers for 100 years due FERPA. Please contact the Special Collections for more information.